export const CHRISTIANRELIGIOUSSTUDIESA2016 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. “Let there be light; and there was light” This statement reveals God’s",
A: "Graciousness",
B: "Sovereignty",
C: "omnipotence",
D: "omnipresence",
answer: "C. omnipotence",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Joseph’s dreams were meant to",
A: "depict God’s will",
B: "reveal Joseph’s future",
C: "reveal Gods sovereignty",
D: "save Egypt from famine",
answer: "A. depict God’s will",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Pharaoh’s fear for the growth and might of Israel made him",
A: "drive the Israelites out of Egypt",
B: "afflict the Israelites with heavy burden",
C: "drown Israelite babies in the Nile",
D: "punish the Israelites with starvation",
answer: "B. afflict the Israelites with heavy burden",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. And he said, cast it on the ground” This instruction was meant to",
A: "convince Pharaoh to harden his heart",
B: "showcase Gods mighty power",
C: "rescue the Jews from bondage",
D: "change the snake into a rod",
answer: "B. showcase Gods mighty power",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The discovery of pomegranates and figs at Eschol gave the spies sent by Moses",
A: "Strength",
B: "Hope",
C: "Disappointment",
D: "Fear",
answer: "B. Hope",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Joshua was chosen to succeed Moses because",
A: "Moses was very old",
B: "God had now rejected Moses",
C: "Moses asked for a successor",
D: "Gods spirit was with Joshua",
answer: "D. Gods spirit was with Joshua",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Deborah was described as a judge because she",
A: "predicted the fall of Jabin",
B: "rescued Israel by killing Sisera",
C: "prophesied that a woman would kill Sisera",
D: "fought to free Israel from Canaanite domination",
answer: "D. fought to free Israel from Canaanite domination",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. In his preparation for the battle against Sisera. Barak chose his troops from the tribe of",
A: "Judah and Issachar",
B: "Zebulun and Naphtali",
C: "Dan and Benjamin",
D: "Gad and Asher",
answer: "B. Zebulun and Naphtali",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. ” Yet his sons did not walk in his ways but turned aside after gains” The “sons” were",
A: "Jonathan and Abinadab",
B: "Hophni and Phinehas",
C: "Joab and Asahel",
D: "Joel and Abijah",
answer: "B. Hophni and Phinehas",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. David said at Ziph that Saul would one day die by one of the following means except",
A: "being smitten by God",
B: "dying a natural death",
C: "perishing in a battle",
D: "taking his own life",
answer: "D. taking his own life",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The people of Jabesh-Gilead honoured Saul by",
A: "protecting his family from destruction",
B: "fighting in the Gilboa war",
C: "paying all their tributes regularly",
D: "giving him a fitting burial",
answer: "D. giving him a fitting burial",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Solomon’s treaty with Hiram, King of Tyre was meant to",
A: "protect Israel when at war",
B: "build Pithan and store cities",
C: "help build the temple",
D: "help establish trade links",
answer: "C. help build the temple",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The religious tension at the time of Ahab was as a result of",
A: "Ahab’s marriage to Jezebel",
B: "Jezebels social injustice",
C: "Jezebels introduction of Baal",
D: "Elijah’s pronouncement of drought",
answer: "C. Jezebels introduction of Baal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The Lord forbid that I should give you the inheritance of my fathers This statement implies that Israelites",
A: "do not donate family property as a gift",
B: "inherited property cannot be mortgaged",
C: "do not sell inherited property",
D: "forbid land transfer to foreigners",
answer: "D. forbid land transfer to foreigners",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following personalities witnessed the reforms of Josiah?",
A: "Hilkiah",
B: "Isaiah",
C: "Ezekiel",
D: "Ezra",
answer: "A. Hilkiah",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Josiah’s reign as king was popular because of his",
A: "religious reforms",
B: "victories in battle",
C: "leadership style",
D: "discovery of the law book",
answer: "A. religious reforms",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Ahab and Gehazi demonstrated the spirit of",
A: "Apostasy",
B: "Selfishness",
C: "Greed",
D: "Treachery",
answer: "C. Greed",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. When Nehemiah heard of the poor state of affairs in Judah. he immediately left to",
A: "build Jerusalem",
B: "became sad and fasted",
C: "took up arms to fight",
D: "mobilized resources for reconstruction",
answer: "B. became sad and fasted",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. King Darius asked men to fear the God of Daniel because he is",
A: "the living God",
B: "the most Supreme",
C: "gracious and Holy",
D: "a loving God",
answer: "A. the living God",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. To Amos, Israel’s expectation of the “day of the Lord” would be a day of",
A: "Happiness",
B: "Punishment",
C: "Rejection",
D: "Forgiveness",
answer: "B. Punishment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Amaziah warned Amos never to prophesy at Bethel again because",
A: "it was the king’s sanctuary",
B: "it showed disrespect to God",
C: "Israel easily broke the Sabbath laws",
D: "Amos belonged to the prophetic guild",
answer: "A. it was the king’s sanctuary",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The prophet whose occupation was the dressing of sycamore tress was",
A: "Ezekiel",
B: "Hosea",
C: "Jeremiah",
D: "Amos",
answer: "D. Amos",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. In the teaching of Hosea, Gomer typifies",
A: "Canaan",
B: "Israel",
C: "Judah",
D: "Assyria",
answer: "B. Israel",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. To Hosea, Yahweh was a God of",
A: "righteousness and justice",
B: "love and mercy",
C: "peace and justice",
D: "purity and righteousness",
answer: "B. love and mercy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The statement “this is my beloved son, with whom lam well pleased was heard during",
A: "Jesus Temptation",
B: "Trial",
C: "Crucifixion",
D: "Baptism",
answer: "D. Baptism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. “Let it be so now for thus it is fitting for us to fulfill all righteousness” The righteous act to be fulfilled referred to Jesus’",
A: "Baptism",
B: "Temptation",
C: "Transfiguration",
D: "Crucifixion",
answer: "A. Baptism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. To be recognized as an economic Messiah, the devil tempted Jesus to",
A: "accept the riches of the world",
B: "jump down from the temple pinnacle",
C: "bow down and worship him",
D: "change stones into bread and eat",
answer: "D. change stones into bread and eat",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. What happened immediately the devil left Jesus after tempting Him?",
A: "The satanic kingdom was overthrown",
B: "The disciples came to strengthen Jesus",
C: "God rejoiced and elevated Jesus",
D: "Angels came and ministered to Him",
answer: "D. Angels came and ministered to Him",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following themes can be associated with the Lords prayer?",
A: "Love",
B: "Forgiveness",
C: "Humility",
D: "Commitment",
answer: "B. Forgiveness",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The three disciples in whom Jesus frequently confided were",
A: "Andrew, Peter and Matthew",
B: "James, Peter and Thomas",
C: "Peter, James and John",
D: "Peter, James and Andrew",
answer: "C. Peter, James and John",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead was meant to show his",
A: "obedience and glory",
B: "power and love",
C: "victory over demons",
D: "victory over death",
answer: "D. victory over death",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. What Jesus demanded from his disciples in Gethsemane was",
A: "prayer and fasting",
B: "vigil and prayer",
C: "love and defence",
D: "love and sympathy",
answer: "B. vigil and prayer",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The man who was compelled to carry the cross of Jesus was",
A: "Clopas",
B: "Barabbas",
C: "Simon of Cyrene",
D: "Joseph of Arimathea",
answer: "C. Simon of Cyrene",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Jesus was brought to Golgotha to be crucified. Golgotha” means a place",
A: "sacrifice",
B: "tribulation",
C: "skull",
D: "death",
answer: "C. skull",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Jesus offered salvation to one of the robbers crucified with Him because the robber was",
A: "Indifferent",
B: "Sympathetic",
C: "Humble",
D: "Repentant",
answer: "D. Repentant",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The field in which Judas Iscariot was buried was known as",
A: "Golgotha",
B: "Akeldama",
C: "Praetorium",
D: "Portico",
answer: "B. Akeldama",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Ananias and Saphira died because of their",
A: "selfishness",
B: "slander",
C: "covetousness",
D: "dishonesty",
answer: "D. dishonesty",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The problem of discrimination in the Early Church was solved by the",
A: "replacement of Judas Iscariot",
B: "death of Ananias and Saphira",
C: "appointment of deacons",
D: "defence of Gamaliel",
answer: "C. appointment of deacons",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Ananias was unwilling to lay hands on Saul because",
A: "God did not instruct him to do so",
B: "Saul’s sin had not been forgiven",
C: "Saul had opposed the Church",
D: "Ananias was not qualified to do so",
answer: "C. Saul had opposed the Church",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The people of Lydda and Sharon turned to the Lord when Peter",
A: "healed Aeneas",
B: "resurrected Dorcas",
C: "invoked the spirit on them",
D: "performed miracles in their midst",
answer: "B. resurrected Dorcas",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. “Why did you go to uncircumcised men and eat with them?” This question was put to",
A: "Aeneas in Lydda",
B: "Cornelius in Caesarea",
C: "Peter in Joppa",
D: "Saul in Tarsus",
answer: "B. Cornelius in Caesarea",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The outpouring of the Holy Spirit was associated with the symbols of",
A: "cloud and stars",
B: "wind and fire",
C: "sound and dove",
D: "flames and dove",
answer: "D. flames and dove",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The first apostolic martyr was",
A: "Judas Iscariot",
B: "James, the brother of John",
C: "Simon Peter",
D: "James, the son of Alphaeus.",
answer: "B. James, the brother of John",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. James said that Abraham, by agreeing to sacrifice Isaac, was justified as a believer, by his",
A: "Faith",
B: "Truthfulness",
C: "Work",
D: "Loyalty",
answer: "A. Faith",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Partiality according to James involved",
A: "loving one another",
B: "discriminating among ourselves",
C: "honouring the poor",
D: "speaking the truth",
answer: "B. discriminating among ourselves",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. James taught that prayers could be answered if Christians pray with",
A: "an open heart",
B: "aggression and force",
C: "peace and forgiveness",
D: "trust and humility",
answer: "C. peace and forgiveness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Peter called on Christians not to retaliate because",
A: "vengeance belongs to God",
B: "God fights for the innocent",
C: "God made light Jesus’s persecutions",
D: "Jesus patiently bore his persecutions",
answer: "A. vengeance belongs to God",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Peter expected elders of the church to lead their flock",
A: "extraordinarily",
B: "timelessly",
C: "selflessly",
D: "bossily",
answer: "C. selflessly",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. To maintain a high moral standard, Peter advised Christians to",
A: "marry fellow Christians",
B: "abstain from social vices",
C: "treat people fairly",
D: "be merciful and kind",
answer: "A. perform good deeds",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Peter taught that Christians should use their freedom to",
A: "perform good deeds",
B: "seek God’s deliverance",
C: "fight their enemies",
D: "honour wicked masters",
answer: "A. perform good deeds",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]